你在被监视着
You are being watched.
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
一台每时每刻都在监视你的机器
a machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
我会知道  因为它是我造的
I know because... I built it.
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖活动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything--
它看到了与普通人相关的暴力罪行
Violent crimes involving ordinary people.
像你一样的普通人
People like you.
而政府认为这些罪行无关紧要
Crimes the government considered irrelevant.
他们不肯作为  所以我决定插手
They wouldn't act, so I decided I would.
但我需要一个搭档
But I needed a partner--
一个有能力介入其中的人
Someone with the skills to intervene.
因为受到当局追捕  我们只能秘密合作
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
你永远找不到我们
You will never find us.
不管你是被害人还是行凶者
But victim or perpetrator,
如果你的号码被列出来  我们就会找到你
If you're number's up, we'll find you.
疑犯追踪 第1季 第8集
Person of Interest S01E08 720p HDTV x264
字幕翻译：YYeTs人人影视
他已经在路上了
He's on his way there now.
我们假设他知道多少
What do we assume he knows?
假设他什么都知道
Assume he knows everything.
请看管好您的行李
All luggage and cartons must be attended at all times.
无人看管的物品将会由运输管理局
Any items left unattended will be removed by,
统一移除和分拣
subject search by the MTA police.
感谢您的合作
Thank you for your cooperation.
东方航空最后登机广播
Final boarding call for the Eastbound express--
18号跑道
Track 18.
东方航空最后登机广播  18号跑道
Final boarding call, eastbound express--track 18.
请及时登机
All aboard.
不 谢谢  我不喝咖啡
No, thanks. I don't drink coffee.
这是煎绿茶
Sencha green tea...
放了一块糖
One sugar.
你还真是观察入微
You've been paying attention.
别紧张  芬奇  不过是杯茶
Relax, finch. It's just tea.
我还没猜到你最喜欢的颜色
I haven't guessed your favorite color yet.
有新号码
New number...
华莱士・奈格尔
Wallace Negel.
1946年生于德国
Born in Germany, 1946,
1980年移民美国
Immigrated to the U.S. in 1980,
在国际出口公司工作
Worked in international export--
信用良好  按时纳税
Good credit, perfect taxes.
等等  这些日期都正确吗
Wait a minute. Are these dates right?
你注意到了
You noticed.
奈格尔名下的账户自从1987年12月起
Negel hasn't made a single electronic transaction
再也没做过任何电子交易
in his own name since december of 1987.
他这24年去了哪儿
So where has he been for 24 years?
他为什么又回来了
And why is he back?
我觉得其实没有奈格尔这个人
I don't think there is a Negel.
外裔  生活平庸
Foreign background, boring life,
需要出差的职业  显然是间谍
A job involving travel-- spycraft 101.
这是个化名
This is an alias.
我用过不少化名
I've used dozens of them.
我觉得奈格尔是个伪装
I think Negel is a cover.
那么  我们从何查起
So, where do we start?
在1987年失踪前不久
Shortly before he disappeared in 1987,
奈格尔在布朗克斯买了一块墓地
Negel purchased a cemetery plot in the Bronx.
我查过了  墓地还在
I've checked. It's still there.
为什么一个不存在的人
Why does a person who doesn't exist
需要一块墓地
need a cemetery plot?
是吧
Right?
应该值得一查
Might be worth a look.
你去哪儿
Where are you going?
如果我们的目标是个80年代的间谍
If we're dealing with a spy from the 1980s,
我知道有个人能提供
I know someone who can provide us
我们需要的非数码信息
with the kind of pre-digital information we need--
在计算机上可查不到
things I can't find on computers.
全是初版
All first editions,
最好的德国历史库
the best available on German history.
记录了冷战的全过程
The entire span of the cold war would do it,
尤其是八十年代
but specifically, the 1980s.
我需要比书上更详细的内容
And I'll be needing something more precise than books.
我不知道你在说什么
I'm not sure what you mean.
比如你去年卖给俄罗斯
How about the Soviet submarine schematics that you sold
情报机关的苏联潜艇图纸
back to Russian intelligence last year?
你向税务局和联邦调查局报告了吗
You register that income with the I.R.S., F.B.I.?
进了监狱就不能继续经营这家书店了吧
It'd be hard to run this store from prison, don't you think?
十八行
Row 18,
二十号
Plot 20.
你要查谁
What was the name?
华莱士・奈格尔
Wallace negel.
德国重新统一之前
Before the country reunified,
东德是全世界监控最严密的国家
East Germany was the greatest surveillance state the world has seen.
史塔西掌控着一切
The Stasi knew everything.
前东德国国家安全局缩写
这我知道  我也搞过监控
I've read about them. I'm a sucker for surveillance.
他们有几百万小时的窃听录音
They had millions of hours of wiretaps,
汗液还有体味的样本
sweat and body-odor samples.
我只要那个化名的真名
I just need a name to go with an alias.
真名是乌里希・科尔
Real name Ulrich Kohl--
一个间谍小组的一员
part of an espionage team.
我读过史塔西的间谍小组的事迹
I've read about the Stasi teams--
科尔所在的小组  跑遍了全世界
Kohl's unit went around the world,
出入于西欧和美国
In and out of western Europe and the U.S.
所以他需要一个美国身份
That's why he needed the American papers.
这个小组专抓东德的叛徒
The team hunted down east German defectors
让他们在开口之将其终结
And neutralized them before they could talk.
"终结"
"Neutralized."
这种人去过的地方
Where guys like him went,
肯定就会死人
People died.
你怎么会知道潜艇图纸的事
How did you know about the submarine schematics?
告诉你了
Told you...
我也是搞过监控
I'm a sucker for surveillance.
看来柏林墙倒下的时候  科尔在欧洲
Looks like Kohl was in Europe when the wall fell.
西德当局在追杀他
Western authorities were hunting him,
所以他跑到苏联藏了起来
So he ran to hide in the Soviet union.
他的妻子  安雅
His wife, Anja,
史塔西总部的秘书
who worked as a secretary at stasi headquarters,
和他一起出逃
ran with him.
但没过多久就丧生车祸
But she was killed in a car accident shortly after.
当时是1987年
That was in 1987.
到了89年  东德解体
By '89, east germany has collapsed.
史塔西不复存在  至于科尔
The stasi no longer exists, and Kohl...
从此杳无音讯
was never heard from again.
他现在这里了
Well, he's here now.
奈格尔的坟墓
Negel's cemetery plot--
里面藏的是个盒子  他几小时前刚挖走
It was a buried stash kit. He dug it up a few hours ago.
你觉得里面有什么
What do you think was in it?
就和我以前会藏的东西一样
If it was anything like the ones I used to bury,
假身份  武器  当然还有钱
I.D.s, weapons, definitely money.
看来间谍科尔重出江湖了
So it seems Kohl, the spy, is back.
豪夫
Hauffe.
抱歉
Sorry?
你有事吗
Can I help you?
你还记得我的安雅吗
这不可能
It can't be you.
我们要好好谈谈
We have something to discuss.
你是新来的吧
You're the new guy, right?
我们去个私密点的地方谈谈
Let's go somewhere private so we can talk.
你是斯坦顿吧  我是...
You're Stanton? I'm--
不  你不是
No, you're not.
计算机系统给你的身份不符合要求
The I.D. Ncs gave you didn't pass muster,
所以你谁也不是
So you're nobody,
也就是说  我来决定你是谁
Which means I get to name you.
威尔逊好不好
Wilson, maybe.
还是算了  先喝一杯吧
No. You should have a drink.
我工作的时候不喝酒
I don't drink when I'm working.
是吗  那现在起改改吧
No? Well, start.
你们这些一级的小哥都一个样
You tier one boys are all the same--
紧张过头
Tense.
而在现实中  这会害死我们
Out here, "Tense" gets us killed.
你以前深入敌后
In your old job, you were behind enemy lines
半年  最多一年吧
for 6, 12 months?
但这个工作  你没有退路
In this job, you never go back,
因为这里没有敌前敌后这一说
Because there is no line to cross back over.
敌人永远都在  明白吗
Never was. Understand?
所以你也放松就可以了
So you may as well get comfortable.
你在路上
When you were in transit,
见到老朋友了吗
Did you see any old friend?
没有
No.
问这个干什么
Why are you asking?
我们知道你的前女友
We know about the ex-girlfriend.
我也说过
Like I told you,
你没有退路
you never go back.
科尔掉的那个硬币
The coin Kohl dropped...
是东德的马克
was an East German mark.
1990年就停止流通了
They've been out of circulation everywhere since 1990.
但我在城里发现了一家绝版硬币兑换店
But I found a rare-coin exchange in the city
今早刚兑换了一整套马克币
where a whole set of marks was sold this morning.
让我猜猜  卖家就是乌里希・科尔
Let me guess, the seller was Ulrich Kohl.
没错
Correct.
他用店里的电话  有人接了就挂掉
He used the store's phone, waited for an answer, hung up.
我追踪了那通电话  查到一个在西城的地址
I traced the call to that address in the west village--
4A公寓
Apartment 4-a.
芬奇  我们晚了一步
Finch, we're too late.
科尔打来电话  是为了确定他在家
Kohl called to make sure he was home.
他被审问过
He was interrogated.
我翻阅了这些记录
I'm going through more of these records.
科尔曾是一个四人小组的一员
Kohl was part of a four man team.
他和他的组长  史戴勒
He shared trigger duties
是组里的杀手
with a team leader named Steiller.
还有个叫沃尼克的伪造者  专门伪造文件
They were backed by a document forger named Wernick...
他们向一个叫豪夫的情报官汇报
And they reported to a case officer
收取命令
named Hauffe for orders.
死了的那个是谁
So who's this dead guy?
公寓租给了一个叫安德鲁・霍恩的人
The apartment is leased to Andrew Honem--
一个未婚离休的建筑师
An unmarried, retired architect.
科尔的工作是杀死所有的叛徒
Kohl's job was killing defectors.
这个家伙可能就是其中之一
Sounds like this guy might have been one.
等等  芬奇
Hang on, Finch.
这个世界上一半的情报部门
Half the intelligence services in the world
曾经都试图追查这些家伙
were tracking these guys at one point.
但他们就像幽灵  无迹可寻
But they were ghosts-- untraceable.
芬奇  那个官员的名字叫什么
Finch, what was the case officer's name again?
豪夫
Hauffe.
这个死者就是豪夫
This dead guy was Hauffe.
科尔杀了他在史塔西的队友
Kohl killed his Stasi teammate.
而他还会继续杀人
And he will kill again.
我不知道你是谁  也不知道你怎么找到这里
I don't know who you are or how you know to be here,
但这一切只是个开始
But this is just the beginning.
而今天会是漫长的一天
Then this is gonna be a long day.
芬奇  这还有其他人
Finch, I got company.
BND  德国情报局的
B.N.D.-- German intelligence.
他似乎知道这里发生了什么
He seemed to know what went down here.
他也很确定科尔会再开杀戒
He also seemed sure Kohl would kill again.
我是弗斯科警探
Detective Fusco.
你有个匿名线报  莱奈尔
Anonymous tip for you, Lionel.
你不要再往这里打我电话
You got to stop calling me here.
西城有一起谋杀案
Homicide in the west village.
凶手应该还要杀更多的人
I think the shooter might have others planned today.
我在现场给你留了个小礼物
I left you a care package at the scene.
我要你查清楚他都知道什么
I need you to find out whatever he knows.
好吧  但我什么做不了
Yeah, well, I can't do anything
除非有人报案
Till someone calls in a crime.
你马上就会接到  "有枪击"
You'll get a call-- "Shots fired."
那儿有枪击吗
Were there shots fired?
现在有了
There were now.
豪夫死了
Hauffe's dead.
科尔的下一个目标是谁
Who's next on Kohl's hit list?
我拿到一个德国探员的加密电话
I took an encrypted phone from that German agent.
所有短信都被屏蔽了  除了他们在读的那条
Every text is blocked except for the one they were reading--
朱利安・温纳
Julian Werner.
温纳是个华尔街的律师
Werner is a Wall street lawyer,
并且
And...
温纳其实就是沃尼克
Werner is really Wernick--
那个伪造者
The forger.
科尔的小组都隐姓埋名生活在纽约
Kohl's entire team is living under aliases in New York.
退隐的绝佳场所吧  芬奇
The perfect place to disappear, right, Finch?
这些人都曾经是他的队友
These people were his teammates.
为什么过了二十年  他还要追杀他们
Why would he be hunting them two decades later?
科尔消失得无影无踪
Kohl vanishes without a trace,
而他的队友却在纽约过上无忧无虑的日子
and his teammates end up living cushy lives in New York.
可能他是为了什么而复仇...
This could be revenge for something--
比我们了解的要复杂得多
maybe more than we know.
-没准和他妻子的死有关  -那场车祸
- The wife's death? - The car crash.
她死于87年  同一年他就消失了
She died in '87, the same year he disappeared.
如果车祸是假的我一眼就能看出来
And I know a staged accident when I see it.
我们得赶在科尔之前找到沃尼克
We need to get to Wernick before Kohl does.
我以为你死了
I thought you were dead.
看来你还带着针啊
Still with the needle, I see.
上面涂了什么
What is it coated with?
发作很快的东西
Something fast.
起码我还能为老同事做到这些
It's the least I could do for an old colleague.
我还有多久
How long have I got?
足够久了
Long enough.
你的口音呢  组长
Where is your accent, Hauptmann?
别人建议我们...
We were advised...
隐没在美国人之中
to blend in America.
今天早上我去看豪夫了
I saw Hauffe this morning.
他是个出色的情报官
He was a good case officer.
这么多年来一直保存着你的信息
He kept information on you all these years.
你还记得
Do you remember...
我的安雅吗
My Anja?
我给温纳的助理打了电话
I called Werner's assistant.
他每天中午都在同一个地方用餐
He has lunch at the same place every day.
我这就去
I'm on my way.
我记得
I remember.
我不知道他们也在追杀她
I didn't know they would go after her, too.
但就算杀了我  她也不能复生  乌里希
But killing me won't bring her back, Ulrich.
我告诉她  我会保护她
I told her I would keep her safe.
你怎么了  乌里希
What happened to you, Ulrich?
我为我的罪孽
I paid...
付出了代价
for my sins,
你的罪  整个组的罪
For yours, for the team.
那些抓住我的人把我关在一个洞里
The people who caught me kept me in a hole,
可我从没停止过思考  策划
But I never stopped thinking, planning.
那是很久以前的事了  我已经忘了
It was long ago. I let myself forget.
对我而言遗忘太奢侈
I did not have that luxury.
我们所作的都是错的
It was wrong what we did.
你接下来要对付史戴勒吗
You'll go after Steiller next?
那么
Then...
保重  老朋友
Be at peace, my old friend.
快报警
Call 911.
速派救护车至19街43号
I need an ambulance at 43 19th street--
卡夫吧咖啡馆
Craftbar cafe.
女士  请靠后
Ma'am, stand back, please.
借过
Excuse me.
脉博微弱  心跳过速  血压 70/30
Weak pulse, but tachycardic-- B.P. is 70/30.
呼吸急促  症状显示内部窒息
Shallow respiration, signs of internal asphyxia.
出现抽搐  癫痫发作了
Convulsions-- guy's having a seizure.
喂
Hey!
你不能呼吸
You can't breathe.
你的鼻腔跟口腔里满是泡沫
You have foam in your nose and your mouth.
是氰化物
It's hydrocyanic acid.
他们在四分钟内就能找到我们
Now, they're going to find us in four minutes.
我能救你  但是你得跟我坦白
I can save you, but you need to talk.
科尔为何而来  为什么他要对付你们每个人
What did Kohl come for? Why is he after all of you?
科尔追杀过他们的线人
Kohl was killing their informants.
美国人要他消失
The Americans wanted him gone.
于是你们就交出了科尔
So you gave them Kohl.
他们给了我们新生活
They offered us a new life.
我们就拿乌里希做了交易
We traded Ulrich.
你曾是他的队友
You were his team...
他的朋友
His friends.
这不是个老兵应得的下场
A soldier deserves better.
我给你打这些  你就有救了
I give you these, and you live.
你叛逃之后发生了什么
What happened after you defected?
他们跟我说科尔投奔了苏联人
They told us Kohl ran to the soviets--
他和安雅
He and Anja.
美国人就去抓他
The Americans went for him.
他们也杀了安雅
They got her, too.
那场车祸
The car accident.
对
Yes.
科尔接下来是要找谁
Who will Kohl go after next?
史...
St--
史戴勒
Steiller...
他跟你们一起叛逃了吗
He defected with the rest of you?
喂  他的化名是什么
Hey? What's his alias?
我救下了那个律师  但是科尔还没完
I kept the lawyer alive, but Kohl's not done yet.
科尔的队友背叛了他  还害死了他老婆
Kohl's team betrayed him, and it got his wife killed.
他们为求自保出卖了他
They preserved themselves over him.
真可真不是一般的私仇
This is as personal as it gets.
那么史戴勒在哪
So where's Steiller?
芬奇  我在豪夫的公寓墙上
Finch, I saw the exact same pin
看到了同样的胸针
In Hauffe's apartment.
德裔美国人协会
The Volks American Society...
是居住在纽约的德裔
Is an organization for New York citizens
美国人的老乡会
Of German heritage.
那个史塔西小组叛逃后
When the Stasi team defected,
他们互相之间不能联系
They wouldn't have been allowed to contact each other.
一个德国人组织能给他们三个人
A German organization would give all three
在公开场合会面的机会
A chance to meet in public.
那么  如果豪夫和沃尼克是会员
So, if Hauffe and Wernick were members...
那么史戴勒肯定也是会员
Then Steiller would have been, too.
两个犯罪现场
There are two crime scenes--
一个在西城  一个靠近华尔街
One in the West Village, the other near Wall Street.
同一个穿着灰西装的老年人
Now, the same senior citizen wearing a gray suit
被人目击从两个现场离开
Was seen fleeing both locations.
华尔街
Wall Street?
那就是早些时候救护车被劫的地方吧
That's where the ambulance was jacked earlier, right?
对
It sure was.
看了那劫犯的外观描述了吗
Read the description of who jacked it?
我追查的那人  他是怎么扯进去的
My guy? How's he involved in this?
而这人出现在第一个案发现场还不省人事
And this guy was found unconscious at the first scene.
伤得真漂亮
Nice bruises.
招了没
He say anything yet,
比如是谁把你屁股踢成了四半
Like who kicked his ass sideways?
有倒是有  两个字
Yeah, two words--
电话
"Phone call."
除此之外都是德语
Everything else is in German.
这些人里有没有你看着眼熟的
Either of these guys look familiar to you?
好了  我们知道你是德国情报人员
Now, we know you're German intel.
我们知道很多
We know a lot.
如果这就是你们知道的  警察同志
If that's all you know, Polizei,
那明显你们知道的还不够多
Then you don't know very much.
那你为啥不跟我们说说那个老年男凶犯
Yeah, why don't you tell me about your homicidal geriatric?
两起罪案  很危险的一个人
Two crimes, a very dangerous man at work,
就派一个人来阻止他吗
And one agent trying to stop a killer?
那我们这些警察同志不帮忙就太说不过去了
It'd be a shame if we polizei couldn't help.
他叫科尔
His name is Kohl.
他是名囚犯
He is a prisoner...
于24年前两国政府交锋的行动中
Arrested in an operation between my government and yours
被捕入狱
24 years ago.
他变老了  白发苍苍  于是他们认为真老了
He had become old, feeble, they thought.
命令下来把他转送
The order was given to transfer him
转移到低强度监管设施
To a minimum security facility.
那我猜是他越狱了
And I'm guessing he escaped.
他聪明又致命
He's smart and lethal.
他杀德国人杀了很多年
And he killed germans for years.
没有什么比抓到他
There is nothing more important
再把他打入天牢更重要的事情了
Than putting him back where he belongs.
那为什么不通报美国政府
Why not involve U.S. Authorities?
处理他并没有走司法程序
He was jailed without trial.
他本不该存在
Kohl isn't supposed to exist.
没人想要个国际纠纷
No one wants an international incident.
你们本就不该在美国境内活动
You aren't supposed to be operating on U.S. Soil.
他所到之处  必定有人要死
Where he goes, people will keep dying.
那就帮我们  我们所求一致
Then help us. We want the same thing.
不要在多说一个字
Don't say another word.
喂  我们正审讯中
Hey, whoa, this is an interrogation.
-你不能进这来  -审讯结束了
- You can't be in here.  - This interview is over.
我是德国使领馆的人
I am from the German Consulate,
这是来自美国国务院的命令
And this is from the U.S. State Department--
要求将此人立即遣返德国
Orders to extradite him back to Germany immediately.
德裔美国人社区网站甚至连
The Volks American website wasn't even using
像样的安全代理都不用
An open SSH secure proxy.
几秒钟时间我就复制了他们的登录表
I cloned their log-in form in seconds.
芬奇  说重点
Finch, the point?
我找到了完整的会员名册
I found the complete membership roster.
豪夫和沃尼克都在上面
Hauffe and Wernick are both on it.
我正在对其它成员进行背景追查
I'm running background checks on the other members.
这里  迈克・斯坦根
Here... Michael Stegans--
纳瓦克的建筑包工头
Construction foreman from Newark.
信用记录是从1988年开始
Credit scores only go back to 1988.
如果符合这个模式
If the pattern follows...
那么这个斯坦根就是史戴勒
Then Stegans is really Steiller.
他在布鲁克林有个建筑工地
He's running a construction site in Brooklyn.
我有他的手机
I have a cell phone.
喂
Hello?
史戴勒先生
Mr. Steiller?
不好意思
I'm sorry.
我想你打错了电话了吧
I-I think you have the wrong number.
没时间装了  你给我听好
There's no time for games. You need to listen.
你还记得乌里希・科尔吗
Do you remember Ulrich Kohl?
他还记得你
He remembers you,
就像他记得其他那些史塔西里的同事
Just like he remembered all his old Stasi colleagues.
他去找你了
He's on his way.
你这是在说一个死人
You're speaking of a dead man.
我知道这天迟早会来
I knew this day would come.
你太强了
You were too good.
我是跟最好的人学的
I learned from the best.
跟你学的
I learned from you.
你曾是我的朋友
You were my friend.
你了解我
You knew me.
了解我妻子
You knew my wife.
她跟我一样相信你
She trusted you as much as I did.
你变了  乌里希
You changed, Ulrich.
我看到了那些任务对你的影响
I watched what the missions did to you--
你眼中的黑暗
The darkness in your eyes.
你相信杀人
You believed in the killing.
你训练我  你成就了如今的我
You trained me. You made me what I was.
我深信我的国家
I believed in my country.
深信你
I believed in you.
我们不能救你
We could not save you.
所以你就抛弃安雅和我  将我们留给那些猎犬
So you left Anja and me to the hounds...
就为了纽约的一间公寓和那点钱
For some money and an apartment in New York city?
我不得不收手
I had to get out.
我够强  我生存下来了
I was strong. I survived.
但是他们对安雅的作为  就
What they did to Anja, though...
你必须为此付出代价
You will pay for that.
慢着  慢着  乌里希
Wait. Wait, Ulrich.
有件事你得知道
There is something you don't know.
我是唯一一个知道的人
I was the only one who knew.
喂
Hello?
安雅还活着
Anja is alive?
我们都叛逃后的几年  她找到了我
She found me a few years after we all defected.
她比任何人都要怕你  乌里希
She was more afraid of you than anyone, Ulrich.
所以  你看
So, you see,
你的复仇根本毫无意义
Your revenge was all for nothing.
芬奇  我们得找出安雅
Finch, we need to find Anja.
我觉得科尔刚刚把她列入了名单
I think Kohl just added her to his list.
车祸是伪造的
The car accident was faked.
她是他的妻子  可她还是背叛了他
She was his wife, and she betrayed him.
对于科尔这样的男人来说
To a man like Kohl,
足够把她列为目标了
That makes her just as much a target.
有个杀手逍遥法外
We got a killer out there,
而我们最好的线索却要被遣返
And our best lead is getting deported.
你不是还有那个孤胆英雄神枪手在找同个人嘛
You still got your vigilante looking for the shooter.
这还不算坏
That's not bad news.
你不能派个杀手去抓另一个  警探
You can't send a killer to catch a killer, Detective.
谁叫那家伙能出成果
Hey, your guy still gets results.
已上路
银色小轿车
牌照 SMH 4642
他们接下来会走小路去机场
They'll take side streets to the airport--
标准章程
Standard procedure.
告诉弗斯科警探把领馆的车载GPS
Tell Detective Fusco to send the GPS tracker number
追踪号码发过来
For the consulate car.
我找到他了
I found their position, Mr. Reese,
但你打算怎么阻止他们
But how do you intend to stop them?
里瑟先生  我表示我现在感到很不自在
Mr. Reese, I'm highly uncomfortable being here.
我表示我现在同感
I'm highly uncomfortable having you here,
但我需要个观察手
But I need a spotter.
报距离
Range it.
不知道  500码
I don't know. 500 yards?
600码
600.
45度斜风
45-degree oblique wind...
四分之三量风速
3/4 value wind speed.
不错啊  芬奇
Very impressive, Finch.
如果你打偏了怎么办
What if you miss?
我可不知道  从没失手过
I wouldn't know. Never have.
停  我们有外交豁免权
Stop. We have diplomatic immunity.
-可我不是外交家  -那你是谁
- I'm not a diplomat.  - Who are you?
我是那个还有时间去救安雅的人
I'm the guy who still has time to save Anja Kohl.
我知道她还活着  但我要知道她在哪
Now, I know she's alive, but I need to know where.
我们无可奉告
This man has nothing to say.
任何交涉都会违反
Any communication would violate--
我什么都做不了  如果你能就去救她
There's nothing I can do. Save her if you can.
安娜・克莱恩  晨边高地公寓的一个地址
Anna Klein--an address in morningside heights.
是安雅
It's Anja.
安雅不在这  科尔
Anja isn't here, Kohl.
她很安全
She's safe...
在你碰不到的地方
Where you can't get to her.
维洛德手枪哈
That's a Welrod, isn't it?
开火时只有73分贝
Only 73 decibels when fired.
但这阻止不了我近你身
But it won't stop me before I get to you.
我中枪之后极度没耐性
And I lose my patience when I get shot.
安雅在哪
Wo ist Anja?
你打算怎么办  科尔
What's your plan, Kohl, hmm?
你是要把她也杀了
You gonna kill her, too...
你自己的妻子
Your own wife?
你还没计划是不是
You don't have a plan, do you?
你两边的颈动脉
Your external carotid arteries--
要是被阻断
Obstruct both...
你就会带着剧烈的头痛醒来
And you wake up with quite a headache.
乌里希
Ulrich?
不可能
It can't be.
他是来找我的吧
He's coming for me, isn't he?
是的
Yes.
现在最重要的是把你置于警方保护之下
What's important now is getting you into police custody.
第八区有个警探
There's a detective at the eighth precinct--
不  慢着  我们还不能走
No, wait. We can't go yet.
那里很安全  我保证
It's safe there. I promise.
不是现在  求你了  我得打个电话
Not yet, please. I need to make a phone call.
相机
A camera...
真赞
It's extraordinary.
史塔西可会为了这种技术杀人
The Stasi would have killed for this technology.
安雅在哪
Wo ist anja?
人旅行的时候  会学到一些东西
When you travel, you pick up things--
技能
Skills...
物品
Items.
他们都嘲笑我
They all laughed at me
嘲笑我学着用这些针头
When I learned to use these needles.
他们都笑不久
They didn't laugh for long.
我
I was, uh...
在坎大哈时曾被叛军巡逻队绑架走
Bagged by an insurgent patrol when I was in Kandahar.
他们试过电击我
They used electricity on me...
16小时
16 hours.
他们想要的不过是我的名字
All they wanted was my name.
我才不管你名字
I don't care for your name.
尺骨神经是人体内
The ulnar nerve is the largest nerve
没有防护的最大一个神经丛
In the human body that is unprotected.
从肩膀一直通到甲床
It goes from the shoulder, to the fingernail beds,
当经过手肘的时候
When it passes through the elbow,
也就是所谓的"麻骨神经"
It's known as the funny bone.
安雅在哪
Wo ist Anja?
别紧张  我们是自己人
Relax. We're on the same team.
更何况  我这衣服要怎么藏枪啊
And besides, where would I hide a gun in this dress?
你是斯坦顿吧
You're Stanton, right?
这是谁
Who's this?
还没决定呢
Haven't decided yet.
米勒说你们喜欢波本威士忌
Miller said you like bourbon.
你知道他们在这边喝什么吗
You know what they drink here?
李子白兰地
Plum brandy.
-米勒可惜了  -他怎么了
- A shame about Miller. - what happened to him?
没有完成任务
Wasn't getting the job done.
上面发话了
Word came down--
是时候该清理门户了
Time to take the gloves off.
那我们能为你们做什么
So... what can we do for you?
我们在调查关于阿利姆・阿西尔
We're looking into reports that Alim Assir
几周前来到国内的消息
was in country last week,
他也许是来确保他的资金
Possibly to secure financing.
我们上周把所有的情报人员
We sent all of our intel
都派到了中情局
in the pouch to Langley last week.
而阿西尔两天前安然无恙地
and Assir made it out of the country safely
离开了美国
Two days ago.
我们要知道为什么
We want to know how.
我们得到的消息也是
That's also in our intel.
正如我们所说  他肯定贿赂了海关一大笔钱
Like we said, he must have paid customs a fortune.
那他又给了你们多少钱
And how much did he pay you?
开玩笑的啦
Kidding.
我刚也说了  你们哥几个也太紧张了
It's like I said-- you boys are too tense.
该好好放松一下了
Here's to taking the gloves off.
你是在开玩笑吧
You've got to be kidding me.
他们没走多远吧
They didn't get very far, did they?
谢谢
Thank you.
还记得我们那位伙计
Remember our friend,
那个被护送去机场的德国特工吗
The german agent and his escort to JFK?
有个西装男在半路上
Apparently a guy in a suit shot them off the road
用把大口径杀器把他们拦了下来
With a high-caliber weapon.
我要去现场
I'm going to the scene,
看看那家伙有没有留下关于科尔的线索
See if my guy left a trail that leads to Kohl.
-我是弗斯科警探  -我要你帮忙
- Detective fusco. - I need your help.
听好  先是他使唤我  现在你也来
Look... First him, now you.
听着  你们两口子可不能随便把我当佣人使唤啊
Look, you guys just can't ring me up like I'm a bellhop.
我们共同的朋友去追捕那个凶手了
Our mutual friend went after your perpetrator,
而他好久没和我联系  肯定出事了
And I haven't heard from him-- something's wrong.
那个男人比我们想的还要危险
This man may be more dangerous than we anticipated.
我要你查一下...
I need you to check on--
听着  我费了不少功夫让卡特相信
Look, I'm doing everything I can to convince Carter
你家那位不是个麻烦
Your boy's not a problem.
现在你又要让我的努力打水漂吗
Now you want me to just walk off the job?
这就得你自己想办法解决了  事态紧急
Then you need to figure something out--it's urgent.
我给你发个地址
I'm sending you an address.
没人接吗
Not getting a response?
我知道你不认识我  但我可以帮你
I know you don't know me, but I'm someone who can help.
你只能杀了我  科尔
You're gonna have to kill me, Kohl.
没有人喜欢杀人
Nobody enjoys taking life.
我很擅长杀人
Killing is what I was good at.
我发现了
I noticed.
你用在沃尼克身上的氰化氢
That hydrogen cyanide that you used on Wernick--
这不是你带来的现成货
You didn't bring that into the country.
是你在这里自己做的吧
You bought that here and mixed it yourself...
没错吧
Didn't you?
你...
You're...
对毒药很熟悉吗
Familiar with poisons?
我接触过一些
Oh, I've had some experience.
我杀过很多人
I have taken lives...
用步枪...
Positioned on a wall...
把他们钉在墙上
With a rifle.
然后史塔西的人来了
Then the Stasi came calling.
他们说  你的国家需要你
They said, "Your country needs you."
他们总是这么说
They always say that.
为了我的国家  我背井离乡
For my country, I left my country...
他们派我到哪  我就杀到哪
And killed wherever they sent me.
就因为这样  我被当做是怪物
For that, I was called a monster.
就算是再黑暗的心  也是人心
Even the blackest heart still beats.
我以前和你一样  科尔
I was you, Kohl.
复仇帮不了你
Revenge won't help.
二十四年来
24 years...
他们把我关在那种不堪的地方
They kept me buried in that hellhole.
我满脑子的念头就是活到今天
I thought about nothing but today.
那明天呢
What about tomorrow?
我必须见她
I have to see her...
我的安雅
My Anja.
臂神经丛是神经网络
The brachial plexus is a network of nerves.
乌里希常常出去工作
Ulrich was always gone for work,
但他和我在一起的时候  他爱着我
But when he was with me, he loved me...
我也爱着他
And I loved him.
我是个间谍的妻子
I was the wife of a spy.
我知道他不能说起他的工作
I knew he couldn't talk about what he did.
有天他回到家
Then one day he came home
说史塔西背叛了他
And said the Stasi had turned on him.
所以你们逃去了苏联
So then you fled to the Soviet Union.
他觉得那里还安全
He thought it was still safe there.
我们分头上路
We traveled separately.
然后美国人找到了我
That's when the americans found me.
他们给我看了照片
Then they showed me photos.
所有那些暗杀
Of all the assassinations.
我告诉自己  是他先骗了我
I told myself that he had lied first.
这么多人死了
So much death...
他怎么能这样
How could he?
美国人伪造了车祸
The americans staged
把我保护了起来
The car accident to keep me safe.
乌里希认为我死了
Ulrich believed I was dead.
但我开始了新的生活
But I started a new life.
这要耗上一整晚
This could take all night.
她的眼睛和她母亲一样
She has my mother's eyes.
别做傻事  乌里希
Don't do anything stupid, Ulrich.
是你藏起来的吗
You hid this?
她叫玛丽
Her name is Marie.
她还不知道你是个怪物
You're not a monster to her yet.
对你我来说已经太迟了
It's too late for you and me,
但她还可以过上正常的生活
But she could have a normal life.
她怎么能瞒着我
How could she keep this from me?
安雅  她怎么可以...
Anja-- how could she take...
他们怎么可以把她从我身边夺走
How could they... take this girl from me?
那女孩有个机会  你不要毁了她
That girl could have a chance. Just leave her be.
同样作为一个职业杀手
As one professional to another...
我很敬佩你的所作所为
I respect what you have tried to do,
但我不能让你跟着我
But I can't have you following me.
不用担心  你哪也去不了
Wouldn't worry. You aren't going anywhere.
弗斯科  快把我松开
Fusco, untie me.
你觉得他会去哪
Where do you think he's going?
去找他女儿
To find his daughter.
不了  真的
No, really.
晚安
Oh, good night.
-回头见  -再见  伙计们
- See you later. - Bye, you guys.
开心点  明天打电话给我
Have fun. Call me tomorrow.
不好意思  小姐
Excuse me, miss.
你能帮我下吗  我在找勒纳堂
Can you help me? I'm looking for Lerner hall.
好的  当然了
Oh, yeah. Sure, um...
打电话给你妈妈
You need to call your mother.
-玛丽  -妈妈
- Marie? - Mom...
有个男人和我在一起  他想和你谈谈
There's a man here with me. He wants to talk to you.
科尔想在公园见面
Kohl wants to meet in the park.
他说如果他妻子单独来  他就不会伤害那女孩
He said he wouldn't hurt the girl if his wife came alone.
想也别想
She's not going anywhere alone.
求你别伤害我
Please don't hurt me.
我只要和你妈妈说几句话
I just need to speak to your mother,
所有这一切就结束了
And then this will all be over.
-你怎么认识她的  -以前认识的
- How do you know her? - From the past.
我认识她和你父亲
I knew her. I knew your father.
我父亲
My father?
你妈妈和你说过他的事吗
Did your mother tell you about him?
在她搬来这里之前
He was a soldier in germany...
他在德国  是个军人
Before she moved here.
他是个勇敢的人
He was a brave man.
在我出生前就死了
He died before I was born.
他是个英雄
He died a hero.
英雄
A hero?
柏林墙倒塌后  他帮她离开了德国
After the Berlin wall fell, he helped her get out.
他帮她得到了自由
He helped her get free
这样我和她才能在这重新开始
So she and I could start a life here.
你认识我父亲吗
Did you know my father?
是的
I did...
我以前认识他
Once.
所有单位注意
All units be advised--
在中央公园附近可能发生劫持案
Possible abduction in the vicinity of central park.
疑犯为男性  六十多岁
Perpetrator-- male, age 60-plus.
被害人为女性  二十三岁
Victim-- female, age 23.
对此我很抱歉
I'm really sorry about this...
真的很抱歉
More sorry than you'll ever know.
你的朋友呢
Where is your friend?
他就在这里
He's right here.
你去哪了  我们收到匿名线报
Where you been? We got an anonymous call.
凶手在公园里吗
Our shooter's in the park?
如果他在这
If he's here,
那我猜我们的义警也在这
I got a feeling my vigilante's here, too.
我们能一箭双雕吗
Think we'll get them both?
你们两个跟他一起过去
Why don't the two of you go with him?
来吧
Come on.
为什么
Why?
为什么你要走
Why did you go?
我发现我丈夫不是我认识的那个人
I found out my husband wasn't the man I married.
他是个杀手
He was a killer.
我无路可走  还怀孕了
I was trapped and pregnant.
我以为自己了解他
I thought I knew him...
但他们告诉我说  他是个怪物
But they told me he had become a monster.
妈妈
Mom...
他是谁
Who is this man?
我害怕你变成了那个样子
I was afraid of the person you had become.
你能原谅以前的我吗
Can you forgive me for the person I was?
我必须见到你
I had to see your face...
你们两个
To see both of your faces.
你告诉她  她父亲的事
You told her about her father--
他是个英雄
That he was a hero,
他救了你
That he saved you.
要不是他
without him...
我们也不会有这种生活
We wouldn't have had this life--
我们都不会
Either of us.
我内心的一部分一直与你在一起
A part of me has been with you always.
乌里希
Ulrich.
我是卡特  快报告状态
This is carter-- report.
谁目击了枪击
Who has a 20 on that shot?
你没事吧
Are you all right?
不  乌里希
Ulrich, no.
不要
No, no.
芬奇  把她们带走
Finch, get them out of here.
你的确应该害怕我
You were right to fear me.
你做的没错
You were right.
空的
Empty.
我不会伤害她
I wouldn't have hurt her.
我从来没有明天可言
I never had a tomorrow.
你怎么知道我会开枪
How did you know I'd shoot?
你和我一样  是个战士
You are a soldier, like me.
他们夺走了我的一切
They took everything I had.
但我的一部分存活了下来
But part of me survived.
那部分
It was...
就是她
Her.
所有单位  我们锁定了枪击地点
All units, we've located source of that shot.
凶手  男性  中枪  身亡
Shooter-- male, down, dead.
B队队长  报告
Bravo team leader, report in.
你觉得这是谁  卡特
Who'd you think it was, carter?
哈珀
Harper.
不  不要哈珀
No, not a harper.
我要你把这些处理掉
I need you to dispose of this
还有他们
And them.
你都没有问他们话
You didn't even question them.
我们没有时间问话
We don't have time for questions--
我们只有答案
Only answers.
这些人收了钱  放跑了一个杀人狂
These men took a bribe to let a mass murderer escape.
你怎么知道是他们
How do we know it was them?
匿名线报
Anonymous source--
非常可靠
Very reliable.
你想知道这是对的吗
You need to know this is right?
在事情变得复杂之前  我告诉你最后一次
I'll tell you one last time before it gets complicated.
这是对的
This is right.
威胁真实存在
The threat is real.
你的国家需要你
Your country needs you.
不要留牙齿和指纹
No teeth, no fingertips.
最后一件事
One last thing...
你没有什么老朋友
You don't have any old friends.
你要是看到他们
You see them...
就当是不认识他们
You don't know them.
我们隐藏在黑暗中  你明白吗
We're walking in the dark here, you understand?
我想我想到了
I think I've got it.
就叫你...
You'll be...
里瑟先生
Mr. Reese.
经历过这一切
After all that,
他还是带着一个
He goes in the ground
根本不是他的名字入土了
Under a name that isn't even his.
德国政府会把这一切都抹掉
The german government will sweep the whole thing under the rug.
乌里希・科尔从不存在
And Ulrich Kohl never existed.
我总是觉得
I always thought I'd die
我会死在一个没人认识我的地方
In a place that didn't know my name.
你觉得别人在乎你是谁吗
You think anyone will care for our names?
我们死后会在乎
After we're dead.
我觉得我们都死了
I thought we already were.
疑犯追踪 第1季 第8集
Person of Interest S01E08 720p HDTV x264
YYeTs人人影视